export const FOODANDNUTRITIONA2023 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. When boiled fish is eaten, digestion starts from the",
A: "mouth.",
B: "oesophagus.",
C: "stomach.",
D: "duodenum.",
answer: "C. stomach",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. Inorder to prevent protein calorie deficiency, toddler is best fed on foods such as",
A: "— soyabean and cod.",
B: "cowpea and rice. .",
C: "bambara beans and wheat.",
D: "kidney beans and sorghum.",
answer: "B. cowpea and rice",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. The insoluble incomplete protein in the connective tissues of meat is known as",
A: "gelatin.",
B: "collagen.",
C: "elastin.",
D: "myosin.",
answer: "B. collagen",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. Essential amino acids that are lacking in the cereals and legumes include",
A: "lysine and arginine.",
B: "methionine and lysine",
C: "Valine and leucine",
D: "Leucine and histidine.",
answer: "B. methionine and lysine",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. During digestion of food, peristalsis takes place in the",
A: "small intestine.",
B: "large intestine",
C: "mouth.",
D: "oesophagus.",
answer: "D. oesophagus",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. The energy need of an individual depends on the person’s",
A: "activity, culture and weight.",
B: "metabolic rate, culture and height.",
C: "gender, weight and metabolic rate.",
D: "weight, gender and height.",
answer: "C. gender, weight and metabolic rate",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. A suitable equipment for baking shepherd's pie ia a or an",
A: "aluminium plate.",
B: "china ware.",
C: "enamel bowl.",
D: "pyrex dish",
answer: "D. pyrex dish",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. The most important factor to be considered when choosing a cooker is the",
A: "brand of the cooker.",
B: "colour scheme of the kitchen.",
C: "kitchen space available.",
D: "aesthetic qualities.",
answer: "C. kitchen space available",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. One of the advantages of the kitchen layout labelled II is that",
A: "— it makes lighting efficient.",
B: "itis suitable for a narrow room.",
C: "it is suitable for a wide room.",
D: "ventilation can get across casily.",
answer: "B. it is suitable for a narrow room",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. Which of the kitchen layouts has the shortestdistance from work centre to the other parts of the kitchen?",
A: "I only",
B: "ll only",
C: "and II only",
D: "I and III only",
answer: "A. I only",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. Which of the illustrated kitchen layouts is the most efficient?",
A: "I only",
B: "II only",
C: "I and II only",
D: "II and III only",
answer: "D. II and III only",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. A suitable cutting tool to remove skin from fruits and vegetables is a",
A: "palette knife.",
B: "utility knife.",
C: "paring knife.",
D: "carving knife.",
answer: "C. paring knife",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. The proportion of egg to milk required for a baked egg custard should be",
A: "2 large eggs to 500 ml of milk.",
B: "4 large eggs to 250 mi of milk.",
C: "6 large eggs to 200 m/ of milk.",
D: "8 large eggs to 150 m/ of milk.",
answer: "A. 2 large eggs to 500 ml of milk",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. The diagrams labelled | and Il are sources of vitamins",
A: "B & K.",
B: "A & D.",
C: "C & K.",
D: "B & C.",
answer: "D. B & C",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. The diagram labelled I is a good source of",
A: "retinol.",
B: "calciferol.",
C: "lysine.",
D: "thiamine.",
answer: "A. retinol",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. The fats obtained from the diagram labelled IV | 22. The greener the leafy vegetable, the higher the is called value of vitamin",
A: "monounsaturated fats.",
B: "polyunsaturated fats.",
C: "saturated fats.",
D: "trans fats.",
answer: "B. polyunsaturated fats",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. Giblet is a term used fo describe the",
A: "poultry.",
B: "cow.",
C: "Pig",
D: "Lamb",
answer: "A. poultry",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. Greasy utensils should be washed in",
A: "baking soda solution.",
B: "water with lemon juice.",
C: "hot soapy water.",
D: "cold soapy water.",
answer: "C. hot soapy water",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. When setting a table, the fork should be placed cutting, washing, cooling and packing.",
A: "on the right hand side. 25. When a glass of orange juice left overnight",
B: "on the left hand side. produces bubbles, it is due to",
C: "between the side plate and jug.",
D: "above the dinner plate. rancidity.",
answer: "B. on the left-hand side",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. Toughness and tenderness of meat depends on the",
A: "height and weight of the animal",
B: "breed of the animal",
C: "age and activities of the animal",
D: "habitat of the animal",
answer: "C. age and activities of the animal",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. Breast milk is considered the best food for infants because it is diced.\nI. readily available. \nII. blanched\nIII. highly nutritious. ,\nIV. sweet and tasty.",
A: "I and II only",
B: "I, II,and III only",
C: "I,II,and III only",
D: "II and III only",
answer: "B. I, II, and III only",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. The greener the leafy vegetable, the higher the valus of vitamin",
A: "B",
B: "C",
C: "D",
D: "A",
answer: "D. A",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. Ametric equivalent measure of 8 level teaspoon granulated sugar is",
A: "16 gm.",
B: "24 gin.",
C: "32.gm.",
D: "40 gm",
answer: "B. 24 gm",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. The sequencial process of preparing vegetable for freezing is",
A: "cutting, washing and packing.",
B: "Blanching,cutting and packing",
C: "cutting,washing and pacvking",
D: "Cutting, washing and packing",
answer: "B. Blanching, cutting and packing",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. when a glass of orange juice left overmight profuces bubbles.it is due to",
A: "rancidity",
B: "discolouration",
C: "fermentation",
D: "oxidation",
answer: "C. fermentation",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. To prevent enzyme action on vegetables to be dried, it should be",
A: "pickled",
B: "iradiated",
C: "diced",
D: "blanced",
answer: "D. blanched",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. Which of these foods spoil faster at room",
A: "Grilled chicken",
B: "Fried yam",
C: "Groundnut soup",
D: "Boiled rice",
answer: "C. Groundnut soup",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. To prevent Salmonella poisoning, it is important )35, The best fat for cake making is",
A: "reheat rice thoroughly before eating.",
B: "cook eggs thoroughly before eating.",
C: "wash vegetables properly before cooking.",
D: "wash fish properly before cooking.",
answer: "B. cook eggs thoroughly before eating",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. Shredded fat is used in the preparation of",
A: "puff pastry.",
B: "suet pastry.",
C: "short crust pastry.",
D: "choux pastry.",
answer: "A. puff pastry",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. The most appropriate person to recommend meals for a patient in the hospital is a",
A: "nurse.",
B: "physician.",
C: "dietician.",
D: "pharmacist.",
answer: "C. dietician",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. In bread making, the use of fat",
A: "makes the product rich and tender.",
B: "helps the crust to brown.",
C: "makes the products colourful.",
D: "binds the dry ingredients.",
answer: "A. makes the product rich and tender",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. When dry heat is applied to cubed sugar it",
A: "makes the product rich and tender",
B: "helps the crust to brown",
C: "makes the product colourful",
D: "binds the dry ingredients",
answer: "B. helps the crust to brown",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. The most important factor to consider when turns yellow and treacles.melts. curamelizes, treacles and burns.",
A: "turns brown and burns.",
B: "dissolves, caramelizes, treacles and burns.",
C: "planning meals for young adults is",
D: "The richness of a cake depends on the quantity of",
answer: "B. dissolves, caramelizes, treacles and burns",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. The richness of a cake depends on the quality of",
A: "fat and eggs",
B: "sugar and flour",
C: "baking powder and milk",
D: "sugar and flour.",
answer: "A. fat and eggs",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. The best fat for cake making is",
A: "ghee.",
B: "lard.",
C: "butter.",
D: "suet.",
answer: "C. butter",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. Draining all water from the food and carefully lowering it into hot oil prevents",
A: "shock.",
B: "bruises.",
C: "choking.",
D: "burns.",
answer: "D. burns",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. The method of cooking that is most appropriate for beef shin is",
A: "grilling.",
B: "stewing.",
C: "steaming.",
D: "roasting.",
answer: "B. stewing",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. Anadvantage of using the cooking method labelled I is that it",
A: "requires little or no attention.",
B: "is a fast method of cooking.",
C: "reduces fat content of foods.",
D: "gives food a distinctive flavour.",
answer: "C. reduces fat content of foods",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. A protective coating of bread crumb is necessary when cooking by the method labelled",
A: "III only.",
B: "II only.",
C: "I and II only.",
D: "I and IIT only.",
answer: "A. III only",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. Basting is associated with the method labelled",
A: "I only.",
B: "II only.",
C: "I and III only.",
D: "I, I and III.",
answer: "B. II only",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. A variety of nutritious dishes can be produced from foodstuffs using different",
A: "food colouring.",
B: "flavoring essence.",
C: "preservation method.",
D: "cooking methods.",
answer: "D. cooking methods",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. Liquid extracted from fruits is referred to as",
A: "drink.",
B: "juice.",
C: "puree.",
D: "punch.",
answer: "B. juice",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. The release of energy from glucose to keep nerves healthy, protect the skin and improve appetite are major functions of",
A: "folic acid.",
B: "ascorbic acid.",
C: "thiamine.",
D: "calciferol.",
answer: "C. thiamine",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. One of the reasons for a weak and light coloured tea is",
A: "short infusion time.",
B: "infusing in hard water.",
C: "boiling of tea bag.",
D: "addition of lemon juice,",
answer: "A. short infusion time",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. In coffee making, coffee grains are brewed for few minutes to",
A: "prevent flat taste.",
B: "reduce m‘lk usage.",
C: "extract the flavour.",
D: "soften the grains.",
answer: "C. extract the flavour",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. The dishes that are eaten by the indigenous people are called",
A: "traditional dishes.",
B: "foreign dishes.",
C: "community dishes.",
D: "family dishes.",
answer: "A. traditional dishes",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. A chef who is able to put left-over foods to good use is exhibiting skills in",
A: "management and planning.",
B: "budgeting and creativity.",
C: "management and creativity.",
D: "budgeting and planning.",
answer: "C. management and creativity",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. An appropriate method of food service for an invalid is",
A: "compromise service.",
B: "family service.",
C: "plate service.",
D: "tray service.",
answer: "D. tray service",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. Which of these is placed to the right of a dinner plate in a formal table setting?",
A: "Bread plate",
B: "Dessert spoon",
C: "Dinner knife",
D: "Salad fork",
answer: "C. Dinner knife",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. For a successful party, an important skill required ola host/hostess is",
A: "meal service.",
B: "table setting.",
C: "good planning.",
D: "invitation designing.",
answer: "C. good planning",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question51",
question:  "51. Information on recipes for local dishes can ‘best be obtained through",
A: "questionnaire.",
B: "observation.",
C: "participation.",
D: "interview.",
answer: "B. observation",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question52",
question:  "52. When a child pays attention whilst the mother is cooking, the behaviour is likened to a method of data collection called",
A: "participation.",
B: "experimentation.",
C: "observation.",
D: "interview.",
answer: "C. observation",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question53",
question:  "53. The main function of consumer agencies is to",
A: "protect the buyer.",
B: "increase sale.",
C: "protect the seller.",
D: "advertise the goods.",
answer: "A. protect the buyer",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question54",
question:  "54. Comparing prices of goods before selection and purchasing is",
A: "market surveying.",
B: "window shopping.",
C: "convenient shopping.",
D: "retail marketing.",
answer: "A. market surveying",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question55",
question:  "55. An example of a rechauffé dish is",
A: "sausage rolls.",
B: "fruit pie.",
C: "shepherd’s pie.",
D: "lemon meringue.",
answer: "C. shepherd’s pie",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question56",
question:  "56. Budgeting before shopping prevents",
A: "impulse buying.",
B: "bulk buying.",
C: "hire purchasing.",
D: "online purchasing.",
answer: "A. impulse buying",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question57",
question:  "57. One of the advantages ofa shopping list toa home maker is that it",
A: "aids impulse buying.",
B: "enhances cheap buying.",
C: "saves time and energy.",
D: "improves bargaining skills.",
answer: "C. saves time and energy",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question58",
question:  "58. The most important factor in making a fulfilling career choice is",
A: "interest.",
B: "lifestyle.",
C: "family expectations.",
D: "working conditions.",
answer: "A. interest",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question59",
question:  "59. The appropriate procedure to manage a catering enterprise is by",
A: "planning, organizing, directing,controlling and evaluating.",
B: "controlling, planning, evaluating,directing and organizing.",
C: "planning, directing and controlling.",
D: "organizing, controlling and evaluating.",
answer: "A. planning, organizing, directing, controlling and evaluating",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question60",
question:  "60. In the process of digestion, diastase converts starch to",
A: "sucrose.",
B: "maltose.",
C: "glucose.",
D: "fructose.",
answer: "B. maltose",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},


]